crowdtilt.com 2014-07-03

# Crowdtilt: Group Fund Anything

Date of Last Revision: September 24, 2013

You can click here to read a summary of changes made to this policy. By continuing to use the Services you agree to the revised policy. 

## Hey Y'all

Thanks for using Crowdtilt! This Privacy Policy explains your rights regarding our collection, use, storage, sharing and protection of personal information, as well as the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update that information. This Privacy Policy applies to Crowdtilt.com (the " **Website** ") and our products, services, content, features, technologies or functions offered on our website and all related sites, applications and services (collectively the " **Services** ") regardless of how you access or use them. The Services are owned and operated by Crowdtilt, Inc. or its subsidiaries (collectively " **Crowdtilt** ," " **we** ," " **us** " or " **our**.")

You accept this Privacy Policy when you sign up for, use or access the Services.

## Updating This Privacy Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our privacy practices. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on the Website or the relevant Services before the change becomes effective. We encourage you to review this page periodically for the latest information on our privacy practices. If you object to any changes, you may close your account. Continuing to use the Services after we publish or communicate a notice about any changes to this Privacy Policy means that you consent to the changes.

## We Want To Get To Know You

When you access the Website or the Services, we request information from and collect information sent to us by your computer, mobile phone, or other device through which you access the Services. The information sent to us may include data on the pages you access, your location, mobile network information, device type, standard web log data, Internet protocol address, and other information. Web log data includes the browser type you're using and traffic to and from our site. When you access Crowdtilt.com or the Services, we also track and collect information about your use of and transactions and activities on them. 

Every computer connected to the Internet is assigned a unique number known as an Internet protocol (IP) address. Since these numbers are usually assigned in country-based blocks, an IP address can often be used to identify the country from which a computer is connecting to the Internet.

Additionally, when you create an account, we also may collect additional information about you. Such information may include:

  * Contact information, such as your name, email address, phone number, and other similar information.
  * Financial information, such as bank account numbers or charge card numbers that you store in your account. 
  * Detailed personal information used to verify your identity, such as your date of birth or social security number. 

When you enter financially sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our Website or Services, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We may obtain information about you from other sources, including credit bureaus, identity verification services, third-party websites, or our payment processors, and combine that with information we collect on our Website or our Services.

You can log into our Services using Facebook Connect or a similar registration or login process that may be enabled from time to time. This service will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us. We may also ask you for additional information when using Facebook Connect, and you will be notified of those requests. The information we may receive varies by site and is controlled by that site. By associating an account managed by a third party with your Crowdtilt account and authorizing Crowdtilt to have access to this information, you agree that Crowdtilt may collect, store, and use this information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

To protect you from fraud and misuse of your personal information, we may collect information about your use and interaction with our Website or Services. As an example, we may evaluate your computer, mobile phone, or other access device to identify any malicious software or activity.

The Services may collect Sensitive Personal Information. " **Sensitive Personal Information** " is information that reveals race, ethnic origin, sexual orientation, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, or that concerns an individual's health. 

Our primary purpose in collecting personal information is to provide you with a secure, smooth, efficient, and customized user experience. We may use your personal information to:

  * Provide you with the Services and with awesome customer support.
  * Process transactions and send you notices about them.
  * Customize, measure, and improve the Services.
  * Resolve disputes and collect fees.
  * Prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities and enforce our Terms of Use.
  * Deliver targeted marketing, service update notices, promotional offers, and campaign updates based on your communication preferences.
  * Compare information for accuracy, compile it with other information for completeness, and verify it with third parties.
  * Send you things in the mail, such as for a campaign or promotion you opted into. 

## We Give You Cookies. Yum

Cookie. Cookie. Like many other websites, we (and the companies we work with) may place small data files on your computer or other device. These data files may be cookies, pixel tags, " **Flash Cookies** " or other local storage provide by your browser or associated applications (" **Cookies**.") We may use these technologies to recognize you as a customer; customize Crowdtilt Services, content, advertising, marketing, and targeting; measure promotional effectiveness; help ensure that your account security is not compromised; mitigate risk and prevent fraud; and promote trust and safety across our Website and the Services. We may use both session and persistent cookies. Session Cookies expire and no longer have any effect when you log out of your account or close your browser. Persistent Cookies remain on your device until you erase them or they expire. We may tie the information gathered to our Customers' or Users' personally identifiable information.

You are free to decline our Cookies if your browser or browser add-on permits, but doing so may interfere with your use of our Website and Services. Refer to the help section of your browser, browser extensions, or installed applications for instructions on blocking, deleting, or disabling Cookies. 

Our third-party partners may employ Cookies. The use of cookies by our third-party partners is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have any control over these cookies.

If you wish to not have personal information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences.truste.com/). However, you may still receive generic ads after opting out. 

## We Think This Is Personal Information

In this Privacy Policy, we use the term "Personal Information" to describe information that can be associated with a specific person and can be used to identify that person. Non-personally identifiable information is information about users that no longer reflects or references an individually identifiable user.

## PCI Security At Its Finest

We transmit and store cardholder data under the most stringent credit card security standard: PCI Compliance Level 1. A PCI-certified auditor verified and awarded us this level of security and compliance.

## Keeping It On The Hush

We want to keep your personal information on the hush. We and our cloud provider protect your information using physical, technical, and administrative security measures to reduce the risks of loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, and alteration. Some of the safeguards leveraged are firewalls and data encryption, physical access controls to the data centers, and information access authorization controls. 

To process your contributions to a Campaign, we may share some of your personal information with the Campaign Admin, including a Political Campaign Admin, or with other people who contributed to the Campaign, such as your name or the amount you contributed. We also may share your personal information with our payments processor, so that we can receive and disburse money related to Campaigns. Such information may include your name, and when you contributed, as well as the contribution amount, the card number, or other bank-related information. 

Additionally, we may share your personal information with:

  * Banking partners as required by credit card association rules for inclusion on their list of terminated merchants (in the event that you meet their criteria,) which includes having Crowdtilt close your Crowdtilt account due to your breaching the Crowdtilt Terms of Use. 
  * Affiliates or other trusted businesses or persons to process personal information for us, or help with our business operations, such as for marketing, fraud prevention, compliance, and technology services, based on our instructions and in compliance with our Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.
  * Credit bureaus and collection agencies to report account information, as permitted by law. 
  * Companies, organizations or individuals outside of Crowdtilt if we have a good-faith belief that access, use, preservation, or disclosure of the information is reasonably necessary to meet any applicable law, regulation, legal process, or enforceable governmental request; to enforce applicable Terms of Use, including investigation of potential violations; to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues; and to protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of Crowdtilt, our users or the public as required or permitted by law, i.e. to comply with a subpoena.
  * Companies we plan to merge with or to be acquired by. Should such a combination occur, we will require that the new combined entity follow this Privacy Policy with respect to your personal information. If your personal information could be used contrary to this policy, you will receive prior notice.
  * Other third parties with your consent or direction to do so. 

Crowdtilt will not sell or rent any of your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes.

If you open a Crowdtilt account directly on a third-party website or via a third-party application, any information that you enter on that website or application (and not directly on a Crowdtilt website) may be shared with the owner of the third-party website or application. These sites are governed by their own privacy policies and you are encouraged to review their privacy policies before providing them with personal information. Crowdtilt is not responsible for the conduct or information practices of such third parties. If you purchase goods or services through a third party on that third-party platform or on the Services using your Crowdtilt account information, we may share your personal information related to your purchase with that third party. Such personal information may include your name, email address, and transaction information (item, amount, time, etc.) However, we will not disclose your charge card number or bank account number to anyone you have paid or who has paid you using the Services, except with your express permission.

We may share aggregated, non-personally identifiable information publicly and with our partners, including publishers, advertisers, or connected sites. For example, we may share information publicly to show trends about the general use of the Services. 

## Talk To Me Maybe

We may combine your information with information we collect from other companies and use it to improve and personalize our Services, content, or advertising. If you do not wish to receive newsletters, campaign updates, or marketing communications from us or participate in our ad-customized programs, simply indicate so in your notifications panel (if the functionality is enabled) or email us at Privacy@Crowdtilt.com. 

We may call you when you provide us your phone number, such as for customer support or to reach out to you regarding the Services. If you do not wish for us to contact you by phone, please let us know at Privacy@Crowdtilt.com.

## Spreading The Word

We give you the option to share things on Crowdtilt and through other services you use, such as through Facebook, Twitter, Google+, and others. Please be aware of your sharing settings on those other services. They may collect your IP address, track pages you visit on our site, and set a cookie so that they function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing them.

Crowdtilt maintains your preferences for the use and sharing of information, including how or when we contact you. Some federal and state laws allow you to restrict the sharing of your personal information in certain instances. Crowdtilt does not share your personal information with third parties for their marketing purposes unless you have given us your explicit consent. 

When you contribute to a nonprofit related campaign, we give you the option to share your information with that nonprofit (for instance, your name, email address, and contribution-related information.) We do not share your information with nonprofits as a result of these campaigns by default. However, when you make a single donation over $250 to a verified nonprofit, we share your information with that nonprofit for the purpose of their sending you a tax-deductible receipt.

For Sensitive Personal Information, we only share this information with third parties with your express consent. 

## Checking Out Your Info And Changing It Up

You can review and edit your personal information at any time by logging in to your account and adjusting your account settings and profile. You can also deactivate or delete your account by emailing us at Privacy@Crowdtilt.com. If you close your Crowdtilt account, we will mark your account in our database as inactive but may retain personal information to improve our Services. If you would like to delete your information after deactivating your account, let us know at Privacy@Crowdtilt.com. We will retain your personal information and sensitive personal information only to collect any fees owed, resolve any disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, prevent fraud, enforce our Terms of Use, or take other actions as required or permitted by law. 

You can import contacts from your Gmail or other email address book to invite them to become a member of our Website or Services. We collect the username and password for the email account you wish to import your contacts from and will only use it for that purpose.

If you choose to invite your friends to our site we will automatically send your friends limited emails on your behalf inviting them to visit the Services. Your friends may contact us at Privacy@Crowdtilt.com to request that we remove this information from our database.

## Blog / Forum

Our Website may offer publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. You can request the removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum by contacting us at Privacy@Crowdtilt.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information. We will inform you if and why this is so. 

## Shine the Light on Me

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, known as the "Shine The Light" law, permits those users who are California residents to request and obtain from us a list of what personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year and the names and addresses of those third parties. You can make such a request only once a year, and you don't have to pay for it. To make your request, send an email to Privacy@Crowdtilt.com or send a written request to Legal Department, Crowdtilt, Inc., 637 Natoma Street, Unit 7, San Francisco, CA 94103.  Crowdtilt should respond to requests within 30 days.  If appropriate, Crowdtilt's response can be a statement that Crowdtilt has not shared any personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. 

## Made In the United States with Love

Any and all information on the Services may be transmitted, processed, and stored in the United States.

## Reach Out To Us About Privacy, And Whatever

We periodically review how we're living up to our Privacy Policy. If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or any complaints, please contact us at Legal Department, Crowdtilt, Inc., 637 Natoma Street, Unit 7, San Francisco, CA, 94103. You can also email us at Privacy@Crowdtilt.com.

## Summary of the Updates to This Privacy Policy:

We have created a more comprehensive Privacy Policy for our users as of September 24, 2013. It replaces our earlier Privacy Policy. We worked hard to create a Privacy Policy we believe reflects the reasonable expectations of our users. We provide this summary of changes to facilitate your review and understanding our present Privacy Policy and practices. However, you should read the Privacy Policy in full: you will be bound by its terms when you view, access, or otherwise use Crowdtilt.

The following are highlights of the revisions to the Privacy Policy:

  1. We expand this policy to cover information of Contributor's without accounts.
  2. We outline a distinction between "Personal Information" and "Sensitive Personal Information".
  3. We provide procedures for updates to our Privacy Policy.
  4. We elaborate further on the information that we collect from users and how we use it. 
  5. We provide additional information about cookies, how you can opt-out of cookie tracking, and how you can opt-out from targeted advertising. 
  6. We provide greater detail regarding with which types of third parties we may share your information. 
  7. We discuss how information we collect from third-party sites is used, such as through Facebook Connect. 
  8. We discuss in greater detail what information is sent to nonprofits designated as a campaign beneficiary. 
  9. We outline possible uses of information you provide and that we may collect from third parties for purposes of fraud prevention or other misuses of the Services.
  10. We provide greater details on how you can modify your settings regarding our communications to you. 
  11. We discuss how we use the email contact information you import to the Services, which is to invite them to the site. 
  12. We now operate a blog. In our new Privacy Policy we include information about what to expect and how to manage your personal information on it. 
  13. We discuss what sharing through third-party sites, such as via social media sites, may mean for your information. 
  14. We clarify further how to deactivate or delete your account. 
  15. We provide contact information for concerns, requests, and questions.
